<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blimp Rock on Stephen Gregory</title>
    <link>https://stephengregory.github.io/tags/blimp-rock/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blimp Rock on Stephen Gregory</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="https://stephengregory.github.io/tags/blimp-rock/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Cupboards Design - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://stephengregory.github.io/art/cupboard-designs-p1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2017 12:22:56 -0230</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephengregory.github.io/art/cupboard-designs-p1/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Life is full of compromises.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When venturing for a new apartment, I found a two bedroom one in an area I liked. The cupboards, however, were white,
flat, and without character.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Boring.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For anyone who &lt;em&gt;knows&lt;/em&gt; me, I am far from boring and always find ways to make life interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a little nudge of inspiration from my girlfriend, Anna, what I saw in front of me instead was a blank canvas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next few months I got to work and played with ideas, off and on, until I had something that I was satisfied with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tl-dr&#34;&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I get into the details, what is below is the final product on the first panel of what will be a full kitchen
piece.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://stephengregory.github.io/images/cupboards/burning-hell-blimp-rock/full.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Full&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://stephengregory.github.io/images/cupboards/burning-hell-blimp-rock/cupboard-final.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cupboard&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://stephengregory.github.io/images/cupboards/burning-hell-blimp-rock/drawers-final.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Drawers&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Music is a huge part of my life. While not musically inclined myself, I find great joy in hearing what others create.
There&amp;rsquo;s something comforting about being able to associate your current mood and feelings with a sound. It can transport
yourself mentally. As it is ubiquitous in my life, I chose it as the theme for my cupboards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The intricate stories from &lt;a href=&#34;www.wearetheburninghell.com&#34;&gt;The Burning Hell&lt;/a&gt; typically take abrupt, humorously
depressing turns. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.blimprockenterprises.com/&#34;&gt;Blimp Rock&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s songs pay a similar attention to detail
to their lyrics, having a familiar quirk to their music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I feel both bands have a similar quirk, I thought it was fitting to combine them in one art piece. This piece
incorporates images from &lt;a href=&#34;https://theburninghell.bandcamp.com/track/i-love-the-things-that-people-make&#34;&gt;I Love The Things That People Make&lt;/a&gt;,
lyrics from &lt;a href=&#34;https://theburninghell.bandcamp.com/track/the-things-that-people-make-pt-2&#34;&gt;The Things That People Make, Pt. 2&lt;/a&gt;
(one of my favorite Burning Hell songs), and images from Blimp Rock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cheap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m living in apartment and have a tendency to move every couple of years. Whatever I create will be custom and
temporary.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Non-destructive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The apartment cannot be damaged in any way and no residue can be left behind.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meaningful.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-artists&#34;&gt;The artists&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past couple of years my music taste has found a home in indie music. Not only does it appeal to me audibly,
but I prefer small venue shows as opposed to stadium shows. It&amp;rsquo;s a much more intimate experience when dancing away
to a band&amp;rsquo;s tunes when they&amp;rsquo;re not a speck on the horizon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I met Mathias and Ariel before a show in February 2016, without realizing they were in The Burning Hell. It was a
Valentine&amp;rsquo;s Day gig, where they played songs from
&lt;a href=&#34;https://theburninghell.bandcamp.com/album/dont-believe-the-hyperreal&#34;&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t Believe The Hyperreal&lt;/a&gt;. Their timing was
spot-on, graciously allowing the crowd to breath catch their breath between laughter (read: frequent side workouts).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://stephengregory.github.io/images/cupboards/burning-hell-blimp-rock/the-burning-hell-ship.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The Burning Hell - The Ship Pub - 2016&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I came across and met Blimp Rock at Lawnya Vawnya 2016, a 5 day indie music festival in St. John&amp;rsquo;s, Newfoundland. Anna
initiated the entire crowd sitting down on the floor of The Ship with Peter Demakos for Sensitive Boys. You only live
once, as they say.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/O422SD3t32Y&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Off stage they are also a kind and fun group. Knowing that makes listening to their music even more enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;process&#34;&gt;Process&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I experimented with a few different combinations of this process, but what follows is what gave me the best results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Completed in Photoshop. I measured my drawers and cupboard and created canvases accordingly. It was more cost
effective to print it out on multiple pages, so I chose a background with a gradient and noise so the joins
would be less noticeable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Print.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Printed at Staples. I split the cupboard design into 3 11x17&amp;rdquo; segments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Coat with spray.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To prevent ink from bleeding when applying the prints to the Con-Tact paper (next step), I applied 6 coats to &lt;strong&gt;both&lt;/strong&gt;
sides. In my experimentation, I found that both sides were necessary. The can recommends 4-5 coats, but I found 6
worked best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I taped my prints to foam boards with some painter&amp;rsquo;s tape I had lying around (to prevent warping) and sprayed them
in a well ventilated space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://stephengregory.github.io/images/cupboards/burning-hell-blimp-rock/spray-prep.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the first spray I mistakenly hung the boards up, leading to some
ink running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://stephengregory.github.io/images/cupboards/burning-hell-blimp-rock/spray.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the remainder I kept the boards laying flat on some chairs (no pictures of this).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Adhere to Con-Tact paper&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I taped the Con-Tact paper to a surface so it did not warp when drying. Following this, I covered the surface in
liquid mod podge and then the back of the piece. I then laid the piece atop of the paper and used my handy-dandy
Memorial University ID card on a 45 degree angle to press the piece the paper. Starting from the center
and pushing outward was the routine that worked best. I started with low pressure until I worked through the
entire piece and then increased the pressure on subsequent rounds until all air bubbles were removed. I left it alone
until dried (~30 minutes).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://stephengregory.github.io/images/cupboards/burning-hell-blimp-rock/adhere-to-white.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cover with clear Con-Tact paper&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to protect the piece in the event of spills, so I covered it in clear Con-Tact (using a card to remove
bubbles). It adds some fogginess to the piece, but from afar you can&amp;rsquo;t really notice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://stephengregory.github.io/images/cupboards/burning-hell-blimp-rock/clear-cover.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Apply to final destination&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I removed any hardware and then cleaned the surface of any dirt and grease that would prevent the paper from sticking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I removed the backing from the Con-Tact paper, lined it up on my surface, and patted it down with my fingers in a
few areas so it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t move. I then took my card to it to flatten it down. I found that this part
was much more forgiving when removing air bubbles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://stephengregory.github.io/images/cupboards/burning-hell-blimp-rock/drawer.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I poked a hole through the hardware holes with a pin, used a sharp knife to cut an &amp;ldquo;x&amp;rdquo; into the pin hole, and
pushed the screws through and put on hardware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://stephengregory.github.io/images/cupboards/burning-hell-blimp-rock/pin.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://stephengregory.github.io/images/cupboards/burning-hell-blimp-rock/drawer-complete.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few hours/days, I noticed some edges peeling off. I applied packing tape along the edges. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t stand
out as much as I had thought.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;cost&#34;&gt;Cost&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mod Podge Matte 8 oz - $9.97&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://stephengregory.github.io/images/cupboards/burning-hell-blimp-rock/mod-podge.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mod Podge Acrylic Sealer Matte 12 oz - $9.97&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://stephengregory.github.io/images/cupboards/burning-hell-blimp-rock/acrylic-sealer.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Clear Con-Tact Paper - 18&amp;rdquo; x 24&amp;rsquo; - ~$8.00&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;White Con-Tact Paper - 18&amp;rdquo; x 24&amp;rsquo; - ~$8.00&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Printed designs - 7 x 11x17&amp;rdquo; @ $0.89 - $6.23&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Foam board - 2 @ $1.50 - $3.00&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;3 Piece Foam Brush Set - 2&amp;rdquo; &amp;amp; 3&amp;rdquo; - $1.25&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://stephengregory.github.io/images/cupboards/burning-hell-blimp-rock/foam-brush.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Total: $46.42 (before tax).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-s-next&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s next?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still have more canvas to work with! So I&amp;rsquo;m getting to work on extending this with other artists who produce
music with a special significance to me (&lt;a href=&#34;catltheband.com&#34;&gt;catl&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.julytalk.com/&#34;&gt;July Talk&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;www.arkellsmusic.com/&#34;&gt;Arkells&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://saidthewhale.com/&#34;&gt;Said The Whale&lt;/a&gt;, and more!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>